Nader Salam IT Manager/Full Stack Developer

GET IN TOUCH

□ nader684@yahoo.co.in

in nader-salam-92479795

+91-7902983757

→ 91-790290.

https://npayeaws.s3.ap-south-1.amazonaws.com/index.html

EDUCATION

M.TECH

KERALA TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY 2017 - 2019

B.TECH

KERALA UNIVERSITY 2002 - 2006

SKILLS

PHP

PYTHON

JAVA

DJANGO

ANDROID

REACT JS

NODE JS

ORACLE

MySQL

MONGODB

POSTGRES

FLUTTER

JAVASCRIPT

VUE JS

AWS (LAMBDA/API)

DYNAMODB

AWS(EC2/S3)

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

IT MANAGER with 13+ years of experience Planning Strategies, building scalable web applications, mobile applications and internal tools that drastically improve efficiency. Throughout my career I've built applications and e- payment sites with a total annual revenue of \$400K.Effectively plan, install, configure and optimize the IT infrastructure to consistently achieve high availability and performance. Deft in interfacing with clients and analyzing their specific requirements.

EXPERIENCE

IT MANAGER

Now Prepay Mozambique S.A | Jan 2015 - Mar 2021

Mozambique

- Designed and Developed the Customized in-house ERP for Now Prepay Mozambique.
- ♦ Designed and Developed the Android App NpayE Epayment App.
- ♦ Designed and Developed Epayment web portal.
- ♦ Integration with banks (BCI & MBIM) for automating Ewallet topup for merchants
- ♦ API Integration with Service Providers to buy Credelec Token for Electricity
- ♦ API Integration with Telecom Providers to buy Pins
- ♦ Configure Active Directory Domain Controller using UBUNTU 14.04 with SAMBA.
- ♦ Configure Mail Server using POSTFIX, DOVECOT and MySQL.
- ♦ Configures Muli Wan Router using UBUNTU.
- ♦ Configured Network Firewall using IP TABLES
- ♦ Configured File Servers.
- Designed and Developed Intranet Application-Customer Support and Inventory Management.
- ♦ ORACLE database Administrator for Rokel And Mobinet Banks -Sierra Leone.
- Serve as project manager for deployment of new technologies with Partners like VODACOM, MOVITEL, MCEL, CREDLEC (Electricity Department of Mozambique).
- ♦ Designing Crystal Reports for the various Departments using Oracle DB
- Research and implement new innovative technologies that are capable of enhancing business productivity or reducing expenses.

FULL STACK DEV FRONTEND DEV BACKENDDEV DATABASE ADMIN API INTEGRATION FILE SERVERS SYSTEM ADMIN PROJECT MANAGER

AWARDS

RESEARCH

ICAICR- CONFERENCE

PUBLISHED PAPER IN ACM

https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1 145/3339311.3339317

PERSONAL DETAILS

NATIONALITY Indian

PASSPORT NO **Z4765030**

MARITAL STATUS
Married

AGE & DOB

36 Years 6th September 1984

LICENSE

Valid UAE, Mozambique Indian LMV license

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR IT ENGINEER

Mint ME (The Mint Corporation) | Apr 2017 - Nov 2020

United Arab Emirates

- Designing and developing E-Payment Web Application project using J2EE standard with JSF, Primefaces and JPA.
- Design and develop reports for various departments using Java HTTPRequest and JPA.
- Design and implemented network solution with UBUNTU 12.0.4 server and Netgear Switch including Firewall using IPTABLES ,DHCP Server, IP aliasing and creating VLANs.
- Designed Nagios scripts to Monitor App Server, DB Server and Web Server running on Linux OS.
- ♦ Proficient in Linux based Scripting like AWK Commandss.
- ♦ Designed and developed automated File Handling app using Java Net beans and Ubuntu Linux Server 12.04..
- Designed Portlets using Liferay portals Using Eclipse Juno.
- ♦ Designed and Developed automated reporting software using PHP and MySql.
- Managed company messaging system including Exchange 2003 with local disk and network attached storage, MAPI, IMAP,SMTP, and Trend Micro anti-spam/virus services.
- Systems monitoring and administration of Servers for day-to-day problems, patches, User Administration, hardware failure, monitoring log files, backup, software up gradation, Configuration changes and documentation.
- Analyzed corporate LAN and WAN to determine what were the major problems and improvements needed to be made to the network infrastructure
- Maintained the infrastructure and application access security through implementing rigorous security features
- Setting up crontab in Redhat ES4 for monitoring various applications from point to point
- Key member in Implementing Debysis Application fro E-payment Solutions and migrating from Qcomm Application for E-PAY.
- Migration from Microsoft Exchange to Google Apps, which was a more cost effective solution.
- ♦ Aided for the implementation of KIOSK machines for Global Business Services

SOFTWARE ENGINEER TURNER AND MILLER | MAR 2008 - MAR 2010

India

Designed and Developed School Management Software.

PROJECT & REPOSITORY LINKS

- https://nadertodo-cli.herokuapp.com/.
- ♦ https://ec2-15-207-55-154.ap-south-1.compute.amazonaws.com/admin2/login.php.
- https://github.com/redan684